<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>interactive graph on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/tags/interactive-graph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interactive graph on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/interactive-graph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Expectancy based on World Bank Indicators</title>
      <link>/graphpost/life-expectancy-based-on-world-bank-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/graphpost/life-expectancy-based-on-world-bank-indicators/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}We used the data from the World Bank Indicators Portal which is an incredibly rich resource to make an animation of the Life Expectancy as a function of Gross Domestic Product per capita. More precisely, this is the value of all final goods and services produced within a nation in a given year, converted at market exchange rates to current U.S. dollars, divided by the average population for the same year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beauty of Animation</title>
      <link>/graphpost/the-beauty-of-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/graphpost/the-beauty-of-animation/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Graphs are a common method to visually illustrate relationships in the data,and they give a clear and compact idea and knowledge of matter contained in, at first sight. Graphs are extremely important and in data analysis they are considered the first statistics to perform.In this post we descrie the R package gganimate an extension of the ggplot2 package for creating animated ggplots. It provides a range of new functionality that can be added to the plot object in order to customize how it should change with time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Graphs</title>
      <link>/graphpost/interactive-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/graphpost/interactive-graphs/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}In this post we are going to create interactive graphs using Plotly.  Plotly allows us to create interactive charts, plot and maps with R. Plotly is designed to build a vast range of visualizations.  Crucially, it has the ability to automatically create interactive charts from the output ggplot2 which is the most abvanced R library to create scientific graphs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>