<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>naive bayes on Andrea Perlato</title>
    <link>/tags/naive-bayes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in naive bayes on Andrea Perlato</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/naive-bayes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP Step by Step</title>
      <link>/mlpost/nlp-step-by-step/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mlpost/nlp-step-by-step/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}This post has the aim to shows all the processes related to the NLP and how to use the Naive Bayes Classifier using Python and the nltk library.We use data from spam detection.
import pandas as pdimport numpy as npimport nltk#import matplotlib.pyplot as plt#import seaborn as snsmessages = pd.read_csv(&amp;#39;C:/07 - R Website/dataset/PY/SMSSpamCollection&amp;#39;, sep=&amp;#39;\t&amp;#39;, names=[&amp;#39;label&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;message&amp;#39;])messages.head()## label message## 0 ham Go until jurong point, crazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Naive Bayes</title>
      <link>/theorypost/introduction-to-naive-bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/theorypost/introduction-to-naive-bayes/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}It is a Probability Classifier. Naïve Bayes is the first algorithm that should be considered for solving Text Classification Problem which involves High Dimensional training Dataset. A few examples are: Sentiment Analysis and Classifying Topics on Social Media. It also refers to the Bayes’ Theorem also known as Bayes’ Law that give us a method to calculate the Conditional Probability: that is the probability of an event, based on previous knowledge available on the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naive Bayes Classification</title>
      <link>/mlpost/naive-bayes-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mlpost/naive-bayes-classification/</guid>
      <description>body {text-align: justify}Naive Bayes is an effective and commonly-used, machine learning classifier. It is a probabilistic classifier that makes classifications using the Maximum A Posteriori decision rule in a Bayesian setting. It can also be represented using a very simple Bayesian network. Naive Bayes classifiers have been especially popular for text classification, and are a traditional solution for problems such as spam detection.
An intuitive explanation for the Maximum A Posteriori Probability MAP is to think probabilities as degrees of belief.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>